Hi. Ah, my name is Dan, I work on the React
嗨。我的名字是 Dan。我在 React
Team and this is my first time in React
Team 工作，这是我第一次参加 React
Conf. [Applause] And so Sophie talked about these
大会。 [掌声] 刚才 Sophie 讲述了这三个
problems that I think most of you have
问题，我想大多数的开发者在 React
encountered in React development. And of
开发过程中都会遇到这些问题。当然，
course we could approach these problems
我们可以逐一来解决
one by one, so we could try to solve them
这些问题。我们可以尝试独立地去
in isolation. But it seems like solving
解决这些问题。但是实际上解决其中一个问题
one of them makes some other one worse.
可能会使其他问题更加严重。
So for example, if we try to solve the
比如我们尝试去解决
wrapper hell by putting more logic into
“包装地狱”的问题，可以将更多的逻辑放到
components themselves, then our
组件里面，那么我们的
components become larger and harder to
组件会变得更大，而且更难以
refactor. And then on the other hand, if
重构。另一个方面，如果
we try to split the components apart
我们尝试将组件拆分为
into smaller pieces and reuse those, then
更小的片段，以方便重用，那么
we end up with more nests than in the
我们的组件树的嵌套更多了，
component tree and we get the wrapper
而且最终又会以
hell again. And finally in either case we
“包装地狱” 收场。最后，无论那种情况，
have all the confusion that comes with
使用 class 都会让人产生
the classes. So we think that this is
困惑。因此我们认为造成这种情况是因为
because these are not three separate
这不是三个独立的
problems. We think that this is, ah, these are
问题。我们认为，这是同一个问题的
three symptoms of one problem. And the
三个症状。问题在于
problem is that React does not provide a
React 没有原生提供一个比 class 组件更
simpler, smaller, lightweight primitive to
简单，更小型，更轻量级的方式来
add state or lifecycle than a class
添加 state 或生命周期。
component. And so once you add a class
而且一旦你使用了 class
component, you can't split it up further
组件，你没有办法在不造成“包装地狱”的情况下,
without introducing the wrapper hell. And
进一步拆分它。事实上，
in fact it's not a new problem. So if you
这并不是一个新问题。如果你
use React for like more than a couple of
已经使用了 React 几年，
years, you might remember then when React
你也许还记得在 React
came out it actually included a solution
刚出来的时候，事实上已经包含了一个解决
to this problem. Ah, it was mixins. So
方案。嗯，这个解决方案就是 mixins。
mixins allow you to reuse some methods
Mixins 能够让你在 class 之间复用
between classes and this way you
方法，通过 mixins 可以
wouldn't have all these wrappers. So
减少嵌套。所以我们要在
should we add mixins back to React? [Yeah ... No...]
React 里面重新把 mixins 添加回来吗？ [对 ... 不...]
That's right, no no, we're not gonna do
对了，不，不，我们不会添加 mixins。
that. Ah, I mean the codes using mixins
啊，我的意思是之前使用
the rounds, it's not like, it's not broken.
mixins 的代码并不是无法使用了。
But we don't encourage using mixins in
但是我们不再推荐在 React 里使用 mixins。
React. And if you curious why, there is a
如果你好奇我们这么做的原因，可以在 React Blog 里面
blog post, uh, that we wrote code called
查看我们之前写的一篇文章，题目是
"Mixins Considered Harmful" on the React
《 Mixins 是有害的》。
Blog, where we explain that we think in
在文章中，根据我们的
our experience, the problems that mixins
实验结果，我们发现 mixins 带来的问题
create are worse than the problems that
远比它解决的问题
they solve. Ah, so that's why we don't
多。因此，我们不推荐大家
encourage using mixins. So perhaps we
使用 mixins。那么也许
could just can't solve this problem
我们解决不了这个问题了，
maybe its inherent to the React
因为这是 React 组件模型固有的
component model. Maybe we should just
问题。也许我们不得不
accept it. [Laughing] Or maybe in there is a, perhaps
选择接受现实。[笑声] 或者也许
there is a different way we could write
有另外一种书写组件的
our components that doesn't suffer from
形式，可以避免
either of these problems. And that's what
这些问题。这也就是今天
I'm going to talk about today. But before
我将要分享的内容。但是在
I start I want to touch a little bit on
开始分享我们在 React 的
the way we approach making changes and
改动和新特性之前，我想先讲讲
additions to React which is a year ago
一年前我们建立的
we set up an RFC process, so RFC stands
RFC 流程，RFC 表示
for request for comments, and it means
request for comments，它意味着
that whenever we want to make or
无论是我们还是其他人
somebody else wants to make a
想要对 React 做出
substantial change or addition to React,
大量变化或者添加新特性时,
they need to write up a proposal with
都需要撰写一个提案，提案里面
detail in the motivation and the
需要包含动机的详情和
detailed design of how this will work.
该提案如何工作的详细设计。
And so that's what we're going to do.
这正是我们要做的事情。
We're excited to announce that we are
我们非常兴奋地宣布：我们已经
ready to present a proposal for how we
准备好了一个提案
can solve these three problems.
来解决这三个问题。
And importantly this proposal does not
重要的是，本提案没有
have breaking changes or deprecations in
不向下兼容的变化，也没有弃用任何功能。
it. It is strictly additive, it is opt-in,
本提案是严格添加性的、可选择的
and it adds some new APIs which happens
而且增加了一些新的 APIs 来
when they try to solve problems. And we
帮助我们解决这些问题。并且我们
would love to hear your feedback on this
希望听到你们对本提案的反馈，
proposal which is why we're, ur, we're going
这也是为什么我们在今天发布本提案
to publish it today. And we thought about
的原因。我们想过很多
many ways we could share this proposal,
发布本提案的方式，
so maybe we just like write off in there ...
也许我们可以写好提案后，
write up an RFC and post it. Um, but since we
提出一个 RFC 然后放在那里。但是既然
were going to run React Conf anyway, we
我们总是要召开 React 大会，我们决定
just decided to, ah, just show it here. And
在本次大会上发布这个提案。那么，
we're going to demo.
接下来进入 Demo 环节。
[Applause]
[掌声]
It already mirrors the displays. Sorry,
我的屏幕已经投在了显示器上。对不起，
technical glitch.
有点技术故障。
Ur, can somebody who understands projectors
呃，有谁会用这个投影仪，来
help me. [Laughing] Ur, can I make it mirror my desktop?
帮帮我。[笑声] 呃，我能复制我的桌面吗？
Please.
请。
(I can do it) Yeah. [Laughing]
(我能) 是啊。 [笑声]
Okay but it doesn't show on the screen, I
好的，但是屏幕上没有显示，我
don't see anything. [Laughing]
什么都看不到。 [笑声]
That's, that's the problem that I had.  [Applause]
这就是我现在的问题。 [掌声]
Okay, disaster averted. [Laughing]
好的，灾难过去了。[笑声]
All right, um, let me check the font size a
好的，嗯，让我来稍微调整下
little bit. Do you see this file? [Yeah] All right.
文字大小。你们能看清吗？ [可以的。] 好的。
So, ah, here is a simple React component, ah, that
那么，我们来看，这里是一个普通的 React 组件，
just it is a row, this is just some
这是一个 Row 组件，这里有一些
styling, and it it renders a person's
样式，然后渲染出一个
name. And so let's say that we want this
人名。我们想要做的是
name to be editable. So how do you do it
让这个名字可编辑。那么我们平时在 React 里
in React normally? Well, like if we want
通常是怎么做的呢？我们需要
to add an input there we need to return
在这里添加一个 input，需要将这些内容放到
this component into a class, add some
class 里面返回，添加一些本地
local state to it, and let that state
state，让 state 来
drive the input. So that's exactly what
驱动 input。这也是我
I'm going to do, uh, that's what we do today.
准备做的事情。这也是现今大家通常做的事情。
So I'm gonna do the export default class
我要导出 default class
Greeting extends React component. And so
Greeting 继承 React.Component。我也
I'm going to use only stable javaScript
只会在这里使用稳定的 JavaScript
syntax. So constructor props, super props.
语法。接下来是 constructor props, super props。
This the state, going to initialize, ur,
在这里把 state 里的 name 初始化为
name to Mary here. And I'm going to
Mary。接下来我要
declare a render method and copy and
声明一个 render 函数，复制一下这段代码然后
paste this.
粘贴到这里。
Sorry.
对不起。
Okay. And so I want this to be instead of
好的。我希望这里不再
just rendering the name, I want this
仅仅渲染 name，我希望这里可以渲染一个
render an input. So I'm replacing
input。我把这里替换为
this by an input, and the value of the
一个 input，然后 input 的值设置为
input is this dot state dot name. And
this.state.name。 然后
if I make a change I want to call this
在 input 输入发生变化时，调用
dot handleNameChange, that's going to
this.handleNameChange，这是我的
be my change caller. And I'm going to
change 回调函数。我把它
declare it here, when the name changes we
声明在这里，当名字发生变化时，
call setState like we normally do. And
像我们通常做的那样调用 setState 方法。然后
we set the name to e dot target dot
将 name 设置为 e.target.value
value. Right. So now if I edit the ... [TypeError In Page] Okay so
对吧。如果我编辑 ... [页面上报了 TypeError 的错误] 好吧，所以我
I, I need to bind ... [Laughing] Sorry I need to bind
应该去绑定 ... [笑声] 对不起，我需要在这里绑定
the events on there. Okay so now I can
events 事件。 好的，现在这样
actually edit it and it works. So a
我们就可以编辑它了，运行正常。
familiar class component is, uh, if you work
这个 class 组件我们应该非常熟悉了。你如果
with React probably right a lot of
使用 React 开发可能会遇到很多类似的
those. But let's take a step back. What if
代码。但让我们后退一步，如果
we didn't have to write a class when we
想要使用 state 时，能否不必须使用
wanted to use state. So I'm not sure how
class 组件？我不确定
that's gonna work. But I'll just start
它如何运行。但是我就准备
with what I know, I want to render an
跟据我的已知来进行，我需要渲染一个
input. So I'm gonna put an input here. And
input。所以我在这里放入一个 input。
the input has a value and that value
这个 input 的 value 的值为
is the current name, so I'll just pass
当前的 name 的值，所以我就传入
name. I don't know where to get name from.
name 值。我不知道从哪里获取 name。
So it doesn't come from props, uh,
它不是从 props 里面来，嗯，
I'll just declare it, and I don't know,
我就在这里声明，我不知道它的值，
I'll fill it in later. Uh, it's gonna have a
之后我再填写这一块。呃，这里应该也有一个
change caller there as well, so I'm going
change 回调函数，我在
to declare onChange handleNameChange.
这里声明 onChange 函数 handleNameChange。
And I'm adding a function here takes an
我在这里添加一个函数来
event. And then here I want to tell React
处理事件。在这里我想要通知 React
to set the name to something, but again
设置 name 值到某处，但又一次地，
I'm not sure how to do that from a
我不确定在 functional 组件里如何实现
functional component. So I'll just call
这个功能。因此我就直接调用
something called setName.
一个叫做 setName 的方法。
With the current input value. And I'll
使用当前的 input 的值。我把它
just declare it here.
声明在这里。
All right, so these two things they're
好吧，由于这两件事情
closely related, right. So one of them is
是密切相关的，对吧。其中一个是 state 里
the current value of the name state
name 变量的当前值，
variable and the other is a function
而另一个是一个函数，
that lets us set the name state variable.
该函数让我们去设置 state 里的 name 变量。
And so because these things are closely
由于这两件事情
related, I'm actually going to put them
非常相关，我将它们
together as a pair of values. So I'm
合并到一起作为一对值。
going to get them together from
我们从某处一同获取到
somewhere. So where do I get them from?
它们的值。所以问题是我从哪里获取到它们？
From React local state. So how do I use
答案是从 React 本地状态里面获取。 那么我如何
React local state from a function
在 function 组件里面获取到 React 到本地状态呢？
component? Well, what if I could just use
嗯，我直接使用 useState
state.
会怎样。
And past the initial state to specify it.
把初始到状态传给 useState 函数来指定它的初始值。
Let's see if this works. Yeah, it works.
我们来看一下程序运行是否正常。是的，运行正常。
[Applause & Cheers]
[掌声和欢呼声]
So let's, let's compare the two
那么我们来比较一下这两种
approaches. So on the left we have a
方式。在左侧是我们熟悉的
familiar class component. This state has
class 组件。这里 state 必须
to be an object. Uh, we bind some event
是一个对象。嗯，我们绑定一些事件
handlers so that we can access. This
处理函数以便调用。在
inside the event handler for this dot setState.
事件处理函数里面使用了 this.setState 方法。
When we call setState it
当我们调用 setState 方法时，
actually doesn't just set the state that
实际上并没有直接将值设置到 state 里面，
merges, the state are the argument into
state 作为参数合并到
the state object. And then when we want
state 对象里。而当我想要获取
to access the state which is this dot
state 时，我们需要调用
state dot something. So in the
this.state.something。那么我们再来
example on the right, we don't need to
看右侧的例子：我们不需要使用
access this dot state dot something.
this.state.something 来获取 state。
Because the name state variable is
因为 state 里的 name 变量
already available in the function. It's
在函数里已经可用。它就是
just the variable. And similarly when we
一个变量。同样的，当我们
need to set the state, we don't need to
需要设置 state 时，我们不需要
access this dot something. Because the
使用 this.something。因为
function that let us set the name is
函数也可以让我们在其作用域内
also available in the scope. So what is
设置 name 的值。那么
useState exactly? UseState is a hook. A
useState 到底是什么呢？ UseState 是一个 hook。
hook is a function provided by React
Hook 是一个 React 提供的函数，
that lets you hook into React features
它可以让你在 function 组件中“钩” 到
from your function components. And
一些 React 特性。
useState is the first hook that we're going
而 useState 是我们今天讲到的第一个
to take a look at today, but there are a
hook，后面还有
few more. So we're going to see them
一些更多的 hook。我们会在后面
later.
看到它们。
All right, so let's go back to our
好的，让我们回到我们
familiar class example. So let's say we
熟悉的 class 例子。我们接下来想要
wanted to add a second field. For example,
添加第二个区域。比如，
for a surname. So the way we normally do
添加一个姓氏的区域。那么我们通常的做法是
this is we add another key to the state.
在 state 添加一个新 key。
And we, uh, I'm going to copy and paste this
我把这行复制然后粘贴到这里。
row. It's gonna say surname now. It's
这里改成 surname。在
going to render a surname, and handleSurnameChange.
这里渲染，这里是 surname 和 handleSurnameChange。
When I copy and paste
我再来复制
this event handler, this will be surname.
这个事件处理函数，把这里改成 surname。
And I need to bind it.
别忘了绑定这个函数。
Okay, Mary Poppins. So we can see that it
好的，Mary Poppins 显示出来了，我们可以看到
works. Uh, so how do we do the same with
程序运行正常。那么我们如何使用 hook 来实现相同的
hooks? So one thing we could do is we
功能呢？我们需要做的一件事情是把我们的 state
could make our state an object. As you
改为一个对象。可以看到，
can see that the state with hooks state
使用 hook 的 state 并不强制其类型
doesn't have to be an object. It can be
必须为对象。它可以是任何原生
any primitive. We could make it an object
类型。我们可以在需要的时候把它
if we wanted to, but we also don't have
变为对象，但是我们不用必须这么做。
to. So conceptually surname is, uh, is not
从概念上讲，surname 和
closely related to state, uh, to the name. So
name 关系不大。所以
what we could do is we could declare a
我们需要做的是，再次调用 useState hook 来
second state variable by calling the
声明第二个 state
useState hook again.
变量。
So I'll declare surname. I can give it any
在这里我声明 surname，当然我可以给它起
name, it's just the variable in my code.
任何名字，因为它就是我程序里的一个变量。
And setSurname. Calling useState and
再来设置 setSurname。调用 useState，
passing the initial state for that state
传入 state 初始
variable 'Poppins'.
变量 'Poppins'。
So again I'm gonna copy and paste
我再一次复制和粘贴
the row. Say surname, the value surname,
这个 Row 片段。改为 surname，值改为 surname，
handleSurnameChange. And when the user
onchange 事件改为 handleSurnameChange。当用户编辑
edits the surname, not sir name, we want
surname 时，不是 sir name，我们
to set the surname.
希望能够修改 surname 的值。
Let's see if this works.
我们来看看能否正常运行。
Yay, it looks like it works. [Applause]
耶，运行正常。 [掌声]
So we can see that we can use hooks more
所以我们可以看到，我们可以在组件里
than once in a component. Let's compare
使用多次 hook。 我们来更详细地比较
the two approaches in more detail. So on
这两种方式。在
the left familiar class component state
左侧我们熟悉的 class 组件里的 state
is always an object, has multiple fields,
总是对象，具有多个字段，
may call setState will merge some
需要调用 setState 函数将其中的
something into that object. And then when
某些值合并进 state 对象中。当我们需要
we want to access it, we do this dot
获取它时，需要调用
state dot something. On the right in the
this.state.something。在右侧使用 hook 的
example using hooks, we use the state
例子中，我们使用了
hook twice. And that declares two state
两次 hook。而且声明了两个
variables: name and surname. And whenever
变量：name 和 surname。而且每当
we call setName or setSurname,
我们调用 setName 或 setSurname，
this tells React that it needs to
这时 React 会接到需要
rerender this component, just like if we
重新渲染该组件的通知，就和
called setState. And so the next time
调用 setState 一样。所以下一次
React renders our components is going
React 渲染组件会
to pass the current name and the current
将当前的 name 和
surname to our component. And then we can
surname 传递给组件。而且我们可以
use it directly without accessing this
直接使用这些 state 变量，不需要调用
dot state dot something.
this.state.something。
All right. So let's go back to our class
好的。我们再回到我们的 class 组件的
example. What else, what other features of
例子。有没我们知道的其他的
React we know? So another thing you
React 特性呢？那么另外一个你可能
might want to do from a component is to
希望在组件里面做的事情就是
read context. So context, in case you're
读取 context。有可能你对 context
not familiar, it's like, ur, kind of like
还不熟悉，它就像一种
global variables for a subtree. So it's
为了子树准备的全局变量。它
useful for things like read the current
在读取当前
theme like visual theme or the current
主题或者是当前
language that the user is using. And it's
用户正在使用的语言很有用。它可以
useful to avoid passing everything
有效避免总是
through props if you need all components
通过 props 传值，当所有组件需要
to be able to read some value. So we're
都需要读取一些相同变量的时候。所以我们
going to import ThemeContext and
将要导入 ThemeContext 和
LocaleContext which I already declared in
LocaleContext，这两个 context 我已经在
another file. And the API you've probably
另一个文件里定义好了。可能你们
most familiar with for consuming context,
最熟悉的用来消费 context，
especially if you have to consume
尤其是消费多个
multiple contexts, is the render prop API.
context 的 API 就是 render prop API。
And it looks like this. So I'm going to
就像这样写。我往下滚动
scroll down here. So we can choose ThemeContext
到这里。我们使用 ThemeContext
Consumer that gives us the theme.
Consumer 获得主题。
In my case, it's just going to be a CSS
在我的例子里，主题就是个简单的
class. So I copy this, all this code
样式。我把这段代码复制，将其全部放入
inside the render prop. And I'm going to
render prop 内部。将
use className equals 'theme' . All right,
className 赋值为 'theme'。好的，
very old-timey. [Laughing]
非常老旧的样式。[笑声]
And I also want to show the current
我也想展示当前的
language, so I'm going to use
语言，因此我将要使用
LocaleContext Consumer. And it's going to
LocaleContext Consumer。我们再来渲染
render another row, so I will copy and
另一行，把这行代码复制
paste this row, can say language.
粘贴到这里，改成 language。
Language. And render it here. Okay, we can
Language。在这里渲染。好的，我们能够看到
see that context works. And that's
context 运行了。这也许是
probably normally consume context. We
最普通的消费 context 情况了。实际上，我们
actually added a more convenient API for
在 React 16.6 版本上增加了一个更加方便的 API
accessing it in classes in 16.6. Ur, but
来获取它。呃，但是
this is how you can see multiple
这就是你们常见的多
contexts. So let's look at the, at how we
context 的情形。那么我们看一下
could do this with hooks. So as we said
如何使用 hook 实现相同的功能。就像我们所
that, state is a fundamental feature of
说，state 是 React
React and this is why you can use state.
的基础特性，因此我们可以使用 useState 来获取 state。
And so if we want to use context, I need
那么如果我们想要使用 context，我需要导入
to import my contexts. So this is gonna
我的 contexts。这里导入
be a ThemeContext, LocaleContext. And
ThemeContext 和 LocaleContext。
now if I want to use context from my
现在如果我想在我组件里使用
component, I can use context. And then to
context，我可以使用 useContext。然后为了
get the current theme, I can use context
获取当前的主题，我可以使用 context
ThemeContext. And to get the current
ThemeContext。为了获取当前的
locale I can use context LocaleContext.
语言，我可以使用 context LocaleContext。
And this doesn't just read the context,
这里 useContext 不只是读取了 context，
it also subscribes the component to
它也订阅了该组件，当 context 发生变化，
updates to this context. But it just
组件随之更新。但现在 useContext 就
gives me the current values, so I can, I
给出了 ThemeContext 的当前值 theme，所以我可以
can put it into my CSS className. And I
将其赋给 className。然后我来添加一个
can add the bro, that's language, and I can
兄弟节点，label 改为 Language， 把 locale 放到
put it here.
这里。
[Applause]
[掌声]
All right, so let's,let's compare the two
那么，让我们，让我们比较这两个
approaches. So this is the traditional
方法。这是传统的
kind of render prop API.
render prop API 的使用方式。
It is very explicit about what it's
非常清楚地显示了它正在做什么。
doing. But it does get a little bit
但是它还包含了一点点的
nested and you encounter this not just
嵌套，而且你遇到这个问题不只是
with context with, with any kind of
使用 context 的情况，你会在任何一种
render prop API. So with hooks, it
render prop API 的使用中遇到这个问题。我们使用 hook
does the same thing. But it's flat. So we
也能做同样的事情。但是代码会更扁平。那么我们
just say we use this context in this
来看一下，我们使用了两个 useContext，
context and we get the theme and locale.
从中我们得到了 theme 和 locale。
And then we can use them. So you might be
然后我们可以使用它们了。那么，你可能
wondering at this point how can React
想问 React 是如何
possibly know. For example, I have this two
知道的。例如，我在这调用了两个
useState calls. So how does it know
useState。所以它是如何知道
which state variable corresponds to
哪一个 state 和调用的哪一个
which useState call. And the answer is
useState 是相对应的。答案是
that React relies on the order of these
React 依赖于这些
calls. This may be a little bit unusual.
调用的顺序。这可能有一点不太寻常。
And, ah, in order for this to work correctly,
为了让它正确地运行起来。
there is a rule that you need to follow
当你在使用 hook 的时候，这儿有一条你需要去遵循的规则。
when you use hooks. And the rule is that
这条规则就是
you cannot call hook inside a condition.
你不能在条件判断里面调用 hook。
It has to be at the top level of your
它必须在你的组件的顶层。
component. So if I do something like, if
如果我做一些类似于 if
props condition, and then I call the useState
props 条件的判断，然后我在这里面调用 useState
hook here. We actually have a
hook。实际上，我们有一个
linter plugin that is going to complain
linter 插件用来提示
that 'This is not the correct way to use
'This is not the correct way to use
hooks'. And we realize that this is an
hooks'。我们意识到这是一个
unusual limitation, uh, but it is pretty
不同寻常的限制，嗯，但是这对 hook 正常
important for hooks tour correctly and
运行十分重要，也
also to enable certain things that I
可以使事情变得更明确，我
think will you will like that I will show
认为你们会喜欢它的，我等会儿会向你们
it later.
展示它。
All right, so let's go back to our class.
那么，让我们回头看看我们的 class。
So the other thing you might want to
你使用 class 想要
reach for the class for is lifecycle
达到的另一件事可能就是生命周期
methods. So the most commonly use case
方法。所以最普通的使用
for lifecycle methods is you want to
生命周期方法的案例就是你想要
perform some side effect such as firing
执行一些副作用，例如发送
off request, performing some kind of
请求，执行某些
imperative DOM mutation interfacing with
调用浏览器 API 监测的必要的 DOM 变化。
the browser APIs. So you might want to
所以，你可能想要
do something like this and you can't do
做一些类似于这个，但是你不能使用在
during rendering, because it's, it's not
渲染阶段做这件事情。因为它还没有
rendered yet. So the way you do
渲染完成。因此，你在 React 中使用
side effects in React is you declare a
副作用的方法是声明一个
lifecycle method like componentDidMount.
类似于 componentDidMount 的生命周期方法。
And then let's say that, uh, if, let me show
那么比如说，嗯，让我向你们展示一下
this. So you see at the top of the screen,
这个。那么，你看到在屏幕的顶部，
it says React App. So there is actually a
它显示的是 React App。这里实际上有一个
browser API that lets us update this. So
让我们更新这个标题的浏览器 API。
let's say we want the tab title to be
比如说我们想要这个页签的标题变成
the name of the person and changed it as
这个人的名字，并且能够随着我输入的值而改变。
I type. And so to set it initially I'm
现在我要初始化它。
going, uh, there is a browser API to do
嗯，这儿有一个浏览器 API 可以做
this, is document.title equals
这件事，那就是 document.title 等于
this.state.name plus space plus
this.state.name 加空格加
this.state.surname. So now we can
this.state.surname。现在我们可以
see it says Mary Poppins. But then if I,
看见这里显示出了 Mary Poppins。但是如果我现在，
if I edit it, it doesn't get
如果我编辑它，它不会
automatically updated, because I also
自动地更新，因为我也
need to implement componentDidUpdate.
需要实现 componentDitUpdate 方法，
For the, uh, for the side effects to be
为了让副作用
consistent with what I rendered. So I'm
和我渲染保持一致。所以我
going to declare componentDidUpdate,
在这里声明 componentDitUpdate,
and just copy and paste this.
然后复制这段代码并粘贴到这里。
All right, so now says Mary Poppins, but if I
那么，现在显示的是 Mary Poppins，但是如果我
started editing it, the document title
开始编辑它，这个文档的标题也更新了。
updates. And this is how we perform side
这就是我们如何在一个
effects in a class.
class 里执行一个副作用的例子。
So how do we do this with hooks? Well the
那么我们要如何用 hook 实现相同的功能呢？
ability to perform side effects is
执行副作用的能力是
another core feature of React components.
React 组件的另一个核心特性。
So if we want to use an effect from our
所以如果我们想要使用的
component. Make an import use effect from
effect，我们需要从 React 里导入一个 useEffect。
React. And then we want to tell React
然后我们要告诉 React
what to do after React has flushed our
在 React 清除组件之后
components to the DOM. So we pass a
对 DOM 做什么。所以我们在 useEffect
function which is where we perform our
里面传递一个函数作为参数，在函数里执行副作用，
effect. So I'm going to say document dot
在这里设置 document.title
title equals name plus space plus
等于 name 加空格加
surname. You can see it says Mary Poppins
surname。可以看到，页面标题显示为 Mary Poppins。
here. And if I start editing it actually
如果我开始编辑它，页面标题实际上也会
updates.
更新。
So what default useEffect runs both
所以，userEffect 默认会在
after the initial render and after every
初始渲染和每一次
update. So by default it is consistent
更新之后执行。所以通过默认的，页面标题
with what here rendered. And you can opt
与这里渲染的内容保持一致。
out of this behavior if like for
如果出于考虑性能原因
performance reasons and, or if you have
或者你有特殊的逻辑，可以选择不采用这种行为。
special logic. And Ryan's talk after me
在我之后，Ryan 的演讲
will touch a little bit on this. So let's
将会谈到一些关于这个的内容。那么让我们来
compare the two approaches. So in the, in the
比较这两个方法。在这个，这个
class we divide method ... we divide the
class 里，我们将函数分开 ... 我们将
logic based on lifecycle method names. So
逻辑分开到不同名称的生命周期方法中。所以
this is why we have componentDidMount,
这是我们为什么会有 componentDidMount,
componentDidUpdate, they fire at
componentDitUpdate 的原因，它们在
different times. And we sometimes repeat
不同的时间上被触发。我们有时候
some logic between them, we could extract
在他们之间重复一些逻辑。我们可以把
it to a function but still we would have
这些逻辑放进一个函数里，但是我们仍然不得不
to call it in two places and remember to
在两个地方调用它，而且要记得
keep it consistent. And with, uh, with the
保持一致。通过，通过使用
effect hook, the effects are consistent
effect hook，副作用默认
by default although there is a way to
具有一致性，而且可以选择
opt out of that. And note is that in the
不使用该默认行为。需要注意的是，
class we need to access this dot state,
在 class 中我们需要访问 this.state，
so there needs to be a special API to do
所以需要一个特殊的 API 来完成
this. But in the effect example, we
这个。但是在这个 effect 例子中，我们
actually don't need a special API to
实际上不需要一个特殊的 API 去
access the state
访问这个 state
variable. Because it's already in the
变量。因为它已经在
scope of the function. It is declared
这个函数的作用域里。它在上面已经声明
right above. And this is why the effect
了。这就是 effect
is declared inside the component rather
被声明在组件内部，而
than the, rather than outside. Because
不是，不是在组件外部的原因。因为
this gives us access to state variables,
这样我们能够访问 state 变量，
ability to set them and anything else
能够去设置他们和任何其他
like the current context value for
例如像当前 context 的值，
example, or any of these contexts.
或者是这些 context。
All right, so let's go back to the familiar
那么，让我们回头看看熟悉的
class example. Ur, another thing you might
class 的例子。嗯，其他你可能需要在 class 里
want to use lifecycle methods for in a
使用生命周期方法实现的就是
class is subscriptions. So maybe you want
订阅功能。你可能想要
to subscribe to some kind of browser API
去订阅一些浏览器 API，
and it gives you some value, for example
它会提供给你一些值，例如
the window size. And you want to update
窗口的大小。你需要组件随着
the state in response to changes to this
这个 state 值的改变更新。
value. And so the way we could do this in
那么我们在 class 里实现这个功能的方法是，
a class, let's say that we want to, ur, that
比如说我们想要，嗯，
we want to monitor the window width. So
我们想要监测窗口的宽度。
I'm going to put width into state. This
我将 width 放进 state 里。使用
window innerWidth browser API. And I
window.innerWidth 浏览器 API 来初始化。然后我
want to render it. Ur, let me copy and paste
想要渲染它。嗯，让我们复制并且粘贴
this. So this is gonna say width. And I'm
这段代码。这里改为 width。我将
going to render it here. It is this dot state
在这个地方渲染它。这里改为 this.state.width。
dot width. This is the width of the
这就是窗口的宽度了，
window, not the width of Mary Poppins. [Laughing]
而不是 Mary Poppins 的宽度。 [大笑]
And I'm going to add a, ur, I'm going to add
我将添加一个，嗯，我将要添加
an event listener, so we need to actually
一个事件监听，所以我们需要真真切切地
listen to changes in the width. So at
监听这个 width 的改变。所以设置
window dot addEventListener.
window.addEventListener。
I'm, I'm going to listen to the resize
我，我将监听 resize 事件，
event, handleResize. And I need to
handleResize。然后我需要
declare this event. And so this is where
声明这个事件。在这里
we're going to update the width state, to
我们更新这个 width 状态，设置为
be window dot innerWidth. And we need
window.innerWidth。然后我们需要
to bind it. And, uh, and I also need to
去绑定它。然后，嗯，然后我也需要
unsubscribe. So I don't want a memory
取消订阅。所以我不想因为保留这些订阅
leak with like keeping these
造成内存泄漏。
subscriptions. I want to unsubscribe from
我想要取消这个事件的订阅。
this event. So the way we do this in a
我们在一个 class 里处理的方式是
class is we create another lifecycle
创建另一个
method called componentWillUnmount. And
叫做 componentWillUnmount 的生命周期方法。然后
I'm going to copy and paste this logic
我将这段逻辑代码复制并且粘贴
here, except this will
到这里，将这里改为
removeEventListener. So we set up an event
removeEventListener。我们设置了一个事件
listener, and we remove the event
监听，并且我们移除了这个事件
listener. And we can verify that this
监听。我们可以
actually works by dragging this. You see
通过拖动窗口来验证。你看到
the width is changing. So it works. So
这个 width 正在变化。运行正常。那么
let's see how could ...  how we could do this
让我们看看如何可以，我们如何
with hooks. So conceptually listening to
用 hook 实现这个功能。从概念上来说，监听
the window width has nothing to do with
窗口宽度
setting the document title. So that's why
与设置文档标题无关。这就是为什么
we're not gonna put it in that effect.
我们没有把它放入这个 useEffect 里的原因。
It's conceptually completely separate
它们在概念上是完全独立的副作用，
effect and just like we could use state
就像我们可以使用多次的 useState 用来
more than once to declare multiple state
声明多个 state
variables, we can use effect more than
变量，我们可以使用多次 useEffect
once to perform different side effects.
来实现不同的副作用。
So I want to subscribe to window
这里我想要订阅 window.addEventListener
addEventListener, resize, handleResize. And
，resize，handleResize。然后
I'm gonna need to keep some state for
我需要保存
the current width.
当前 width 的状态。
So I'm actually going to declare another
所以，我将声明另一组
state variable. So I'll say, ur, width and
state 变量。所以这里声明 width 和
setWidth. We get them by using state with
setWidth。我们通过 useState
window innerWidth as the initial value.
设置他们的初始值为 window.innerWidth。
And now in my handleResize function,
现在我把 handleResize 函数
I'll just declare it here. Because it
声明在这里。因为它
isn't used anywhere else. And it's going
没有在其他地方被调用。然后用
to setWidth to the current width. Um, I
setWidth 来设置当前的 width。嗯，我
need to render it. So I'll copy
需要去渲染它。所以我复制
and paste this row. I'm gonna say width.
并粘贴这个 Row。这里改为 width。
And finally I need to clean up after
最后我需要在这个
this effect. So I need to specify how to
effect 之后去清除它。所以我需要指定如何
clean up. And again conceptually cleaning
清除。从概念上说，清除
up is part of this effect. So this effect
也是这个 effect 的一部分。所以这个 effect
has a clean up place. And the order, you,
有一个清除的地方。这个顺序，你，
the way you can specify it is that any
你可以指定如何清除订阅的方法是，
effect can optionally return a function.
effect 可以选择返回一个函数。
And if it does return the function, then
如果它返回一个函数，那么
React will call this function to clean
React 将在 effect 之后
up after the effect. So this is where we
调用这个函数进行清除操作。所以这就是我们
unsubscribe.
取消订阅的地方。
Okay, let's just verify that this
好的，让我们验证一下
actually works. Yay. [Applause]
它能否正常运行吧。耶！[掌声]
So let's compare the two approaches. On the left, we have a
那么让我们比较这两个方法。在左边，我们使用了一个
familiar class component, ur, nothing
熟悉的 class 组件，嗯，在这没有
surprising there. We, we have some side
令人惊喜的东西。我们，我们有一些
effects, some related logic is split
副作用，一些相关的逻辑是分开
apart. So we can see that document title
的：我们可以看到文档的标题
has been set here. But it's also being
在这里被设置，但是它在这也
set here. And then we subscribe to an
被设置了。并且我们在这订阅一个
effect here.
effect，
Sorry, subscribe to the event here, but we
抱歉，在这订阅这个事件，但是我们
unsubscribe here. So these things need to
在这里取消订阅。所以这些事情需要
be in sync with each other. And then this
相互保持同步。而且这个
method contains two unrelated methods
方法包含了两个不相关的方法，
two unrelated lines. So that me in the in
在这不相关的两行。因此，我，在，在
feature make it a bit difficult to test
未来有点难以单独测试它们。
them in isolation. But it looks very
但是它看起来非常熟悉。
familiar. So that's, that's nice. So this
所以，这，这也不错。那么这段
code probably looks less familiar. But
代码看起来可能会就不那么熟悉了。但
let's take another look at what's going
让我们来看一看这里发生了什么。
on here. Ur, in with hooks we separate code
嗯，在 hook 中，我们分离代码
not based on the lifecycle method name,
不是基于生命周期函数的名字，
but based on what the code is doing. So
而是基于这段代码要做什么。所以
we can see that there is one effect
我们可以看到这个有一个 effect，
which is we updated document title.
我们用来更新文档的标题
That's one thing, this component can do.
这是一件这个组件能做的事。
And then there is another effect which
这里有另一个 effect，
is subscribing to the window resize
它订阅了 window 的 resize 事件，
event and update in the state when it
并且当 window 的大小发生改变时，state 随之更新。
changes. And, ur, this effect has a cleanup
然后，嗯，这个 effect 有一个清除
phase which means that when it's time to
阶段，它的作用是
remove this effect React removes it and
移除这个 effect 时，React 取消事件监听
avoids the memory leaks. And if you've
从而避免内存泄漏。如果你
been carefully watching, you might notice
一直仔细观察，你可能注意到
that since effect run after every render,
由于 effect 在每次渲染之后运行，
we're just gonna keep resubscribing. So
我们会重新订阅。
there is a way to optimize this. Uh, so
有一个方法可以优化这个问题。嗯。
default is to be consistent, ur, which is
默认是一致的，嗯，这
important. If you for example use some
很重要。如果你，例如在这使用一些
prop here, I need to resubscribe to a different id from
prop，我需要去重新订阅一个不同的 id
props or something similar. But there is
，该 id 来自 props 或类似的地方。但是这儿有
a way to optimize it and opt out of this
一个方法去优化它，并且可以选择不用这个
behavior. And Ryan in the next
行为。Ryan 在下一个
talk will mention how to do it.
演讲中将会提到如何去实现它。
All right, so there is one more thing that I want
好的，我在这里还想要演示
to show here. So this component is
另外一件事。现在组件已经
getting pretty large, and it's fine. So we
非常庞大了，这也没有太大的问题。我们考虑到
expect that since you now can do more in
在 function 组件中你们有可能
function components, they will get larger
做更多的事情，组件会变得更大，
and that's totally okay. Um, but you might
但也完全没有问题。嗯，但是你有可能
want to reuse some of that logic in
想要复用其他组件里面到一些逻辑，
other components or extract it or test
或者是想要将公用的逻辑抽取出来，或者是想要
it separately. What's interesting though
分别测试。有趣的是，
is that hooks calls uh, they are just
hook 调用实际上就是
function calls. And components they are
函数调用。而且组件就是
just functions. So how do you share your
函数。那么你们是如何在
logic between two functions? You extract
两个函数之间共享逻辑呢。你们会将公用逻辑提取到
it to a different function. That's what
另外一个函数里面。这也是我将要做的
I'm going to do. You're going to copy and
事情。我把这段代码复制
paste this. And I'm going to create a new
粘贴到这里。我要新建一个
function called useWindowWidth and I'll
叫做 useWindowWidth 的函数。然后把它
just paste it here. And so we need the
粘贴到这里。我们需要
width in our component in order to
组件里面的宽度，以便能够将其
render it. So I need to return it from
渲染。因为我需要在这个函数里面
this function, which is the current width.
返回当前宽度。
And then I can go back up. And I can say
然后我们回到上面的代码，这样修改：
const width equals useWindowWidth.
const width = useWindowWidth。
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Cheers]
[欢呼声]
So what is this function? We didn't do
那么这个函数是什么呢？我们并没有做
anything special, we just extracted the
什么特别的事情，我们仅仅是将逻辑提取到了
function. Uh, but there is a convention here.
一个函数里面。呃，但是这里有一个约定。
So we are calling this function a custom
我们把这种函数叫做 custom
hook. And by convention custom hook names
hook。按照约定，custom hook 的名字
always start with use. And so there are
需要以 use 开头。这么约定主要有
two reasons for this. We're now going to
两个原因。我们
like read your function name or to
会读你的函数名或
string it or anything like this. But it
修改函数名称。但是这是一个
is an important convention because first
重要的约定，因为首先
of all, this lets us lint automatically
以 use 开头来命名 custom hook，可以让我们自动检测是否
for violation of the first rule that I
违反了我之前说过的第一条规则：
described about call hooks unconditionally.
不能在条件判断里面使用 hook。
So if we didn't know if something is a
因此如果我们无法得知哪些函数是
hook, then we wouldn't be able to do that.
hook，那么我们就无法做到自动检测。
And another reason is that if you just
另一个原因是，如果你查看
look at the component code, you kind of
组件的代码，你可能会想要
want to know if some function can have
知道某个函数里面是否含有
some state inside of it. So it's
state。因此
important that there is a convention is
这样的约定很重要，
, okay, use something it means that it's
，好的，以 use 开头的函数表示这个函数是
potentially stateful. And here width gives
有状态的。在这里 width 变量给了
us the current width and subscribes us to
我们当前的宽度并且订阅了
updates through it. So if we wanted to, we
其更新。如果我们想，我们
could even go further. It's probably not
可以更进一步。在这个例子里面
necessary in this example, but I just
也许并不必要，但是
want to give you like a sense of what
我想要给你一个思路。
you could do. Um, so let's say like maybe
嗯，我们也许
setting the document title was a bit
设置文档的标题的功能会更加
more complicated and you wanted to like
复杂，你希望能够把它的逻辑提取
extract it or test it separately. So I
出来并单独测试。那么我把这段代码
could just copy and paste this. And I
复制过来粘贴到这里。我可以
could write a new custom hook. I'm gonna
写一个新的 custom hook。我把这个 hook
call this one useDocumentTitle. And so
命名为 useDocumentTitle。由于
the name and surname don't really make
name 和 surname 在上下文作用域里
sense in the scope's context. We just want
没有意义。我希望调用
to call this title. And this is going to
标题，标题就是一个
be an argument, so custom hooks are
参数，由于 custom hook 就是
javascript functions, so they can take
javascript 函数，因此他们可以传递
arguments and return values or not
参数，返回值或者
return. So it is going to take title as
不返回。这里我把 title 设置为
an argument. And now in my component, I
参数。然后在组件里面，
can say useDocumentTitle, name plus
使用 useDocumentTitle，参数为 name 加上
surname.
surname。
In fact, I could go even further. So in
事实上，我可以更进一步。在这个例子
this case it's totally unnecessary, but
中是完全没有必要的，但是
again, maybe our inputs were more
同样的道理，也许我们的输入框会更加的
complicated, maybe we were tracking
复杂，也许我们需要追踪
whether the input was focused and
输入框的聚焦或
blurred, whether it has been validated,
失焦事件，或者输入框是否被校验过、
submitted and so on. So maybe we had some
提交过等等。也许我们还有
more logic there we wanted to pull it
更多的逻辑想要从组件中
out of our components. Um, and reduce
抽离。嗯，而且想要减少
duplication. And there is already some
重复代码。这里已经有了重复
duplication, so we have this like almost
的代码，这两段事件处理函数
identical event handlers. So what if we
几乎一样。那么我们如果
could just, um, I'm going to delete one of
，呃，我把他们删除一段，
them and extract the other one. I'm going
然后提取另一段。我要创建另一个
to create a new hook, that I'm going to
新 hook，把它命名为
call useFormInput. So this is my change
useFormInput。这个 hook 是我的
handler. Now I'll also copy and paste
change 处理函数。现在我把这个声明复制
this declaration. So this defines the
粘贴到这里。这里定义了
state for this input. And so it's no
输入框的状态。这里不再是
longer name and setName. I'll just call
name 和 setName。我把这里改为更通用的
generically value and setValue. It's
value 和 setValue。我把初始
going to take the initial value as an
值作为
argument. And this is just going to be a
参数。这里改为
handleChange, and this will setValue. So
handleChange，这里改为 setValue。那么
what do we want to get in order to use
我们该如何做在我们组件里面
this, uh, use an input in our component? We
使用输入框呢？我们需要
want to get the current value, and a
获取当前的 value 和
change handler. These are the things that
change 处理函数。这是我们需要
we attach to the input. So let's just
赋给输入框的。所以我们就在 hook 里面
return them. Um, return value and onChange
返回他们。嗯，返回 value 和 onChange
handleChange. So now if we go back up, we
handleChange 函数。我们回到组件里面，
can say name equals useFormInput Mary.
这里改为 name 等于 useFormInput，参数 Mary。
The name is going to be an object with
这里 name 变为了一个对象，包括
value and onChange fields. And surname
value 和 onChange 函数。这里 surname 等于
is useFormInput Poppins. So this is now
useFormInput，初始化参数 Poppins。这里改为
going to be name dot value and surname
name.value 和 surname.value
dot value because this is where the
因为这两个值才是
string is. And so now I can remove this,
我们需要的字符串。接下来我把这里
and I can spread over the name object.
删除，然后将其改为 spread 属性。
Someone is laughing. [Laughing] All right. Let's just
有人在笑。[笑声] 好的。我们
verify it and break it, yeah it works. So
来验证一下，是的，运行正常。每次
each time we call a hook, its state is
我们调用 hook，其状态都是
completely isolated. And this is because
完全独立的。这是因为
we just rely on the order of hook calls,
我们依赖调用 hook 的顺序，而不是
and not on names or anything. So you can
通过名称或其他方式来实现的。所以你可以
call the same hook multiple times. Each
多次调用相同的 hook。每次调用都会
call will get its own local state. So
获取其自身的本地状态。
let's compare the two approaches for
我们最后一次来比较
the last time. Um, so on the left we have a
这两种方式。嗯，在左侧我们熟悉的
familiar class component, it has some,
class 组件例子里，在一个对象里面
some state in an object, bind some
有一些 state，绑定了一些
methods, has some logic spread across
方法，有一些逻辑分散到了
different lifecycle methods as a
不同的声明周期方法里面，这些逻辑是
bunch of event handlers, um, uses, um, uses
一串事件处理函数。嗯，我们用了
something things from the context and
来自 context 的内容来
render stuff. Um, pretty familiar. And on the
渲染内容。嗯，这种情况我们相当熟悉了。在右侧窗格
right pane, this may not look like the
里面，和我们常见的
React components were used to. But it
React 组件不同。但是它是
kind of makes sense. Even if you don't
有意义的。即使你并不知道
know how these functions are implemented.
这些函数是如何实现的。
You can see okay it uses to form inputs,
你可以看到，这个函数就是用来组织输入框的，
uses some context to get theme and
这个函数用了 context 来获取主题和
locale, it uses the window width and
本地语言，这个函数使用了窗口宽度和
document title, and it renders a bunch of
文档标题，然后渲染了一连串的
stuff. And if we want to. We can scroll
内容。如果我们想了解更多，我们可以滚动窗口
further and we can see okay, so this is
到下面，可以看到，这就是
how the input works, this is how setting
输入框如何运行的代码，这里是如何设置
the document title works, this is how the
文档标题的代码，而这里是如何设置并订阅
window width subscription works. Or maybe
窗口宽度的代码。或许
this could be an npm package and you
这里可以是一个 npm 包，实际上
don't actually need to know that. All we
你没有必要了解它是如何实现的。我们可以
could pull it back into a component or
将它在组件里面调用，或者在组件之间复制粘贴
copy and paste between components. So
他们。
hooks give you custom hooks, give you the
Hook 提供了 custom hook，灵活提供了
flexibility to create your own
创建你自己的
abstractions that are not ...  they do not
抽象函数的功能，custom hook 不会让你
inflate your React component tree and avoid
的 React 组建树变得庞大，而且可以避免
the wrapper hell.
“包装地狱”。
[Applause]
[掌声]
And importantly these are not two
而且重要的是，这两个例子并不是
separate applications. So this is
独立的两个应用。实际上，这两个例子是在
actually one application. So I have this
同一个应用里面。我把这个窗口
window open just to demonstrate that
打开的目的就是想要展示
classes can work side by side with hooks.
class 可以和 hook 并肩工作。
And while hooks represent our vision for
而 hook 代表这我们对 React 未来的
the future of React. Uh, we don't want to
期许，嗯，但是我们并不想
make breaking changes like this. So we
做出不向下兼容的改变。我们还需要
need to keep classes working. Ur, let's go
保证 class 可以正常运行。
back to you the slides. All right, now
我们回到幻灯片上来。好的，这张幻灯片
this is a slider you can actually tweet. [Laughing]
就是你们可以发 tweet 的片子。 [笑声]
We present the Hooks proposal to you
今天我们向你们展示了 Hook
today.
提案。
Uh, hooks let us to use all React features
呃，hooks 让我们可以在不使用 class 的情况下
without having to write a class. They do
使用 React 的众多特性。而且我们没有
not deprecated classes, but you have the
弃用 class，但是我们给你们提供了一个
option to not have to write them. We
不去写 class 的新选择。我们打算尽快
intend to cover all use cases for
完成使用 hook 来替代 class 的全部
classes with hooks as soon as possible.
用例。
There are a few that are missing, but
目前还有一部分缺失，但是我们正在
we're working on them. And hooks let you
处理这部分内容。而且 hook 能够让大家
reuse stateful logic, extracted out of
复用有状态的逻辑，并将其从组件中提取
components, tested separately, reuse it
出来，分别测试，在不同
between different components without
组件之间复用，并且可以避免
introducing the wrapper hell. And again
引入“包装地狱”。重要的是，
importantly it's not a breaking change,
hook 不是一个破坏性的改动，
completely backwards compatible, strictly
完全向后兼容，是严格
addition ..., uh, additive. And you can find the,
添加性的。你可以从
we wrote the documentation for hooks, so
这个 url 查找到我们关于 hook 的
you can find it at this url. Um, and
文档。嗯，我们希望
we want to hear from you, the React
听到你们的反馈，React
community wanna hear what you think
社区希望了解到你们对 hook 的
about hooks. Um, whether you like them or not.
想法，嗯，无论你们喜欢与否。
And we realize that it's pretty hard to
而且我们发现如果不让大家实际使用 hook，
give feedback without actually trying
就会很难收到反意见。
them. So we built them, and we released
所以我们将 hook 构建发布到了
sixty ..., um, sixteen seven alpha. It's not a
React 16.7 alpha 版本上。这个不是一个
major release, it's a minor release. But
主要版本，是一个小版本。但是在这个
in alpha where you can try hooks. And
alpha 版本，你可以尝试使用 hook。
we've been trying them in production at
而且我们在 Facebook 的生产环境已经测试
Facebook for about a month. So we don't
了一个月，因此我们认为
expect major bugs there. But the APIs
不会有大的缺陷。但是 hook 的 API
themselves may change together with your
可以根据你们的反馈意见
feedback. And I asked you not to rewrite
进行调整。而且我不建议你们
anything like not to rewrite their whole
把整个应用使用 hook 来
apps with hooks. Because first of all it's,
重写。因为首先，hook 目前还在
it's a proposal. And second because
提案阶段。第二个原因，我个人认为，
personally I, I find that it takes a bit
使用 hook 的思维方式
of a mind shift to start thinking in
需要一个思想上的
hooks, and it might be a bit confusing if
改变，也许刚开始你们尝试把
you try to just take a class component
class 组件转为 hook 写法会比较
and convert it. But I do encourage you to
困惑。但是我推荐大家
try using hooks in some of the newer
尝试在新的
code that you write in and let us know
代码里使用 hook，并且让我们知道
what you think. So,
你们是怎么想的。那么，
thank you.
谢谢大家。
[Applause]
[掌声]
So in our view hooks represent our
在我们看来，hook 代表着
vision for the future of React. But I
React 的未来。但我认为
think they also represent the way we
这也代表着我们推进 React 发展的
move React forward. And that is we don't
方式。那就是我们不进行
do big rewrite. Uh, we want the new patterns
大的重写。嗯，我们希望我们更喜欢的新模式
that we like better to coexist with the
可以和旧模式
old patterns, so that we can have gradual
并存，这样我们就可以进行渐进
migration and adoption just like you can
迁移并接受这些新模式，就像你们渐进
gradually adopt React itself. And this is
接受 React 本身一样。这也差不多
almost the end of my talk. Uh, I want to end
是我演讲的结尾了。但是最后，我想讲讲
it on a personal note. So I started
一些我个人的观点。我从
learning React about four years ago. And
四年前学习 React。我遇到的
one of my first questions was why JSX.
第一个问题就是为什么要使用 JSX。
Uh, but my second one of the next questions
嗯，我第二个问题是
was I can figure out what does the logo
React 的 logo 到底有
have to do with React. So the project is
什么含义。React 项目没有起名叫
not called Atom, it's not a physics
“原子”（Atom），它并不是一个物理
engine.
引擎。
Um, so one interpretation is that it's kind
嗯，有一个解释是，React 是
of upon on
基于
reactions, so atoms participate in
反应的（reactions），原子也参与了
chemical reactions, reactions -> React. Um, but
化学反应，因此从 reactions 到 React。呃，
it's not a claim with React actually
但是 React 没有官方承认过
got it, uh, I found a different interpretation
这种说法。嗯，我发现了一个对我来说
that made more sense to me. And the way I
更有意义的解释。我是
think about it, uh,
这样思考的，呃，
we know that physical matter consists of
我们知道物质是由
atoms. And we've learned that it's the
原子组成的。我们学过物质的
types of these atoms and their
外观和行为是由原子
properties that determine how the
和其内部的属性
physical matter looks and behaves. And
决定的。而
React has taught me something similar,
React 在我看来是类似的，
that you can take a user interface and
你可以使用 React 来构建用户界面，
you can split it into these independent
将其拆分为叫做组件的独立
units called components, and it's the
单元。用户界面的外观和行为
types and properties of these components
是由这些组件及其
that can describe how the user interface
内部的属性
looks and behaves.
决定的。
What's ironic though is that the word
具有讽刺意味的是，原子（atom）
'atom', it literally means indivisible. So
一词，字面上的意思是不可分割的。当
when scientists just discovered atom for
科学家们首次发现原子
the first time, they thought this is the
的时候，他们认为原子是
smallest thing we're gonna find. But
我们发现的最小的物质。但是
later they discovered an electron, which
之后他们就发现了电子，电子是
is a smaller particle inside the atom.
原子内部更小的微粒。
And it turned out it actually electrons
后来证明实际上电子
explain a lot about how atoms work. And I
更能描述原子运行的原理。我
kind of feel the same way about hooks. I
对 hook 也有类似的感觉。我
don't feel like hooks are a new feature.
感觉 hook 不是一个新特性。
Rather I feel that hooks provide me with
我感觉 hook 提供了使用
access to React features that I already
我们已知的 React 特性
know, such as state and context and lifecycle.
的能力，如 state 、context 和生命周期。
And I feel like hooks are a more
而且我感觉 hook 就像
direct representation of React. And that
React 的一个更直观的表现。Hook
they really explain how a component
在组件内部真正解释了组件
works inside. And I feel like they've
是如何工作的。我感觉 hook 一直
been hiding in plain sight for four
在我们的视线里面隐藏了
years. And in fact if you look at the
四年。事实上，如果看看
React logo, you can see those electron
React 的 logo，可以看到电子的
orbits there. So maybe hooks have been
轨道，而 hook 好像一直就
there all along. Thank you.
在那里。谢谢。
[Applause]
[掌声]
Dan, thank you so much. Sophie thank you
Dan，非常感谢你。Sophie，也谢谢
as well.
你。